Max!
Come here.
Ven aquí.
The sisters are waiting for you.
Las hermanas esperando te estamos.
She is Frey.
Ella es Frey.
She is also new here.
Ella también es nueva aquí.
Do you know to read?
¿Sabes leer?
This is a giraffe.
Era una jirafa.
They lived in Africa.
Vivió en África.
You can read?
¿Sabes leer?
Yes.
Si.
There are many robot servers,
and they serve you all day.
If you live there,
you'll never get sick or old.
I'll take us there one day.
Really?
Yes, I promise.
Frey...
and...
Max.
Forever.
Max,
Have you been stealing again?
¿has estado robando de nuevo?
It breaks my heart.
Me parte el corazón.
Why do you do it?
¿Por qué lo haces?
To save up?
¿Para ahorrar?
To some day buy a ticket,
Para algún día comprarte un pasaje,
and go up there?
E ir ahí arriba?
That place is not for you,
Ese lugar no es para ti,
or me.
Ni para mí.
It's not fair, sister.
No es justo, hermana.
Why can't I go?
¿Por qué no puedo ir?
There are things that can't be explained.
A veces hay cosas que no se explicar.
And we just have to accept them.
Y sólo tenemos que aceptarlas.
Pero hay una cosa que sé.
But one thing I know for sure.
You're a very special person.
Eres una persona muy especial.
One day you'll do something marvellous.
Un día que vas a hacer algo maravilloso.
You were born for it.
Estás destinado para ello.
My little Max.
Mi pequeño Max.
Max, friend!
Max, amiguero!
Off to work?
Gotta get up early, to work that line.
Wanna make the world a better place?
¿Quieres hacer del mundo un lugar mejor?
That's real funny, I have a job.
Funny.
Chistoso.
Please children!
Por favor niños!
Come on, you think I got money?
Do I look like I have money?
Come on, that's why I work.
Come on, por eso trabajo.
How about you,
you got a little money?
Come on, what you got in there?
What you got?
Wait a minute.
Oh, it's 5 bucks.
Hey, wait a minute I got...
I got 5 bucks, I'm rich.
You have money? You have money?
¿Tienes dinero? ¿Tienes dinero?
I can buy my ticket to Elysium?
¿Puedo comprar mi boleto para Elysium?
Alright.
Please form an orderly queue.
Your bus has arrived.
I don't have anything.
Checked.
Move on.
Morning, Officer.
Extensive criminal history.
Multiple felonies.
What's in the bag?
Hair products, mostly.
I'm just fucking with...
Hey! Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Hey I'm just going to work, man.
There's nothing in the fucking bag.
Come on, I...
Misdemeanor citizen disobedience.
Just going to work, man.
Come on.
Checked.
Nothing in there, is it?
Zero-tolerance policy
applies to all citizens.
No shit?
You must report immediately
to your parole officer.
Thank you, Citizen.
No, thank you.
Frey, fracture in bed 2.
Thank you.
Max?
Frey.
I thought you were...
When did you get back?
Been back for a while.
I see things haven't changed.
No, no this wasn't even my fault.
Of course not.
Let me have a look.
How is it?
Pretty bad break.
So you're a nurse?
You did it!
Yeah.
That's great.
You still stealing cars?
No, God, I don't do any of that
stupid shit anymore.
I work at Armadyne.
On the line, you know? Working...
Frey, they need you up on the 3rd floor.
Be right there.
So, you know, now that you're back...
Just a second.
Dominica,
can you take over here?
Hey, listen. Now, you know,
because you're back and everything.
Max, I'm so sorry I have to go.
It's good to see you.
Stay out of trouble.
I do.
Look...
I get, I know why you left
the neighborhood, I understand.
If I was as smart as you
I would have left too.
Have dinner with me. Just...
I'll settle for a coffee.
No.
Have I got to break my other arm
to get attention?
Stop.
Because I will do that.
My life is complicated, Max.
I just, I... I...
I miss you.
My shift ends at 8 on Wednesday, Ok?
Yeah, alright.
Coffee.
Yeah, coffee. Right.
Get out of here.
All parolees must have
weapons inspection.
Hello.
Before we start, I'd
just like to explain...
Max da Costa,
violation of Penal Code 2219.
Today at bus stop 34-B.
Yes, that's exactly what I wanted
to talk to you about.
See I believe there is been
a misunderstanding.
Immediate extension of parole
by a further 8 months.
Wait, What? No, no, no. No. No.
I can explain what happened.
I just made a joke.
And, you know...
Stop talking.
Police officers noted
violent and antisocial behavior.
We regrettably must extend parole.
Elevation in heart rate detected.
Would you like a pill?
No!
Thank you,
what I'd like to do is expl...
Stop talking.
Personality matrix suggests a 78.3%
chance of regression
to old behavior patterns.
Grand theft auto,
assault with a deadly weapon,
resisting arrest.
Would you like to talk to a human?
No, I am ok. Thank you.
Are you being sarcastic and/or abusive?
Negative.
It is a federal offense
to abuse a Parole Officer.
Understood.
Hey!
Da Costa!
You're late for your shift.
Yeah man, I had a little thing...
Oh. No, no, no, no. You can't
work with that. You're out.
No, no, no, no, I'm good, man.
I can work. I can work.
This is bit, It's coming off later today.
So you're good?
I'm fine. I'm good!
You're good?
Ok, I'm docking you half a day.
Yeah, alright.
You know, you're lucky
to have this job.
No weapons detected.
You are clear for entry.
Please keep your workstation tidy.
A tidy workstation
is an efficient workstation.
Hey check it out, man.
I think he likes you.
Think he got his face peeled today?
He looks good.
Attention: All workers
must reach weekly quotas.
Please report any unsafe
activity to your supervisor.
If we don't have a clear path to up-side,
our investors are going
to start losing a lot of confidence.
What do you think I've been doing here,
on Earth?
Do you think I enjoy breathing this air?
No, of course, but...
I'm doing everything possible...
to restore profitability to this company.
The company that I built.
Now, if you will excuse me,
I have to not speak to you
people any longer. Thank you.
Closing 34!
Firing 34!
Tag her, quick!
Let's go, let's go, let's go,
we don't have much time.
We have 3 transporter codes, Spider.
Ok, pull them up on screen.
Codes have been accepted.
Fire up the shuttles!
We're going up!
Welcome.
Hello, ma'am.
Take a look at the garden.
We will, thank you.
Hello, Madame Delacourt.
Hello.
Hi, Ivan, how you've grown.
Hi. You alright?
Fine.
Are the kids here?
Yes, with Dominica.
I have a present for you.
Wanna see?
It's in the salon.
Go get it with your mother.
Super, thank you.
It's, by the canape.
See you later.
Ma'am, would you care
for a refreshment?
Demand's cancelled.
Sorry for disturbing you, ma'am.
We have a number of
undocumented ships in-bound.
Good afternoon,
Defense Secretary Delacourt.
3 undocumented ships are
approaching Elysium airspace.
Emergency orders 6
and 7 are now in effect.
Protocol 22/B39...
Attention, incoming vessels.
You have made unauthorized
entry into Elysium airspace.
Dad!
It's Ok!
We will be forced
to take immediate action.
You are in violation
of Elysium airspace.
Standard warning didn't work.
15,000 kilometers and closing.
What do you want us to do, ma'am?
Activate Kruger.
Ma'am, according to Executive Order 355 we
are unauthorized to use our assets on earth
I am authorizing you.
Yes, ma'am.
Agent 32, over.
We are sending the packet, over.
Welcome, Agent Kruger!
10,000 kilometers and closing.
Sending coordinates to asset.
Three target data.
Shoot them down!
Green light, 21-B.
Green light.
Missiles away!
Shit.
Impacto inminente.
Ten.
Eight. Seven. Six.
Five. Four. Three.
Two.
One.
Two ships destroyed.
46 total casualties.
Impact in 5.
Last missile was a miss.
Ridiculous!
Only one made it.
Ma'am, the ship has breached
our atmosphere.
First undocumented ship
just touched down.
I want everyone coming out
of that vehicle apprehendeded.
Identification confirmed.
Scanning.
Reconstruction process initiating.
No!
We have 32 arrests,
13 casualties, and 2 illegals
at large, Ma'am.
Reconstruction complete.
Mum!
You are under arrest,
under the 68-C Immigration Act.
All illegals are now in custody, ma'am.
Yes.
Send them to deportation,
Get them off this habitat.
Secretary Delacourt, please report
to President Patel immediately.
Secretary Delacourt,
report to President Patel.
What up, man?
What happened?
¿Qué te pasó?
It always is.
Lo es siempre.
The police, man.
Are you ok?
Yeah, don't worry about it.
Max, I got to talk to you.
Ok you...
You know...
No!
What do you mean no?
You didn't even hear
what I was gonna say.
Alright, go ahead. Go ahead.
Ok.
You know the house
of Doseta's up on the hill?
Yeah, the one with all the guns.
Yeah, they have five cars.
New ones.
It's gonna be three of us.
Tomorrow, at lunch.
Lunch time?
That's the plan?
Jesus Christ.
You have a better plan?
Yeah, just take one guy.
Go before the sun comes up.
You take the two fastest cars.
You torch the batteries
on the other ones of...
Fuck you. Fuck you!
I got you, cojone!
Oh please. You're the best.
Give me one year. Just one...
I'm not the best.
I'm not going back to prison.
One year, please!
Look at you!
You used to be a legend
and now what?
The time is 5:50 am.
No weapons detected.
You are clear for entry.
Closing 34!
Attention!
Doors are not aligned.
Worker attend.
Hey!
You're holding up the line.
No, no, I got a jam!
What've you done, da Costa?
No, I'm just trying to reset.
Let me take a look. Let me look.
The pallet's pinched.
Yeah, It didn't move.
Just go in there.
No, I mean...
Look, you go in there right now...
or we'll find someone who will,
and you can go clean out your locker.
Come on, man.
No, no. That's the deal, Ok?
In you go!
Let's go, people, back to work!
Fuck.
No, no, no, stop!
Hey!
Hey, come on, vamos!
Let's go! Let's go!
¡Vamos! ¡Vamos!
Too late!
Extraction!
They started the fight.
Ellos comenzaron la pelea.
I just want to live there.
Solo quiero vivir allí.
Do you see how beautiful it is from here?
¿Ves lo hermoso que nos parece desde aquí?</I.
Yes.
Si.
Good.
Bueno.
For now look beautiful,
Ahora ve lo hermosos,
we see each other from there.
Que nos vemos desde allí.
Keep this.
Guárdalo..
Now it belongs to you.
Ahora te pertenece.
So you never forget,
Para que nunca olvides,
where you come from.
De dónde vienes.
What happened?
You have been exposed
to a lethal dose of radiation.
You will experience
catastrophic organ failure.
In five days time, you will die.
What is going on?
Why has production stopped?
He's been exposed...
Don't breathe on me.
Cover your mouth.
I'm sorry, sir.
Does his skin fall off, or something?
I don't want to replace the bedding
in there. Just get him out.
Yes, sir.
Right, thank you.
Mr. Carlyle, your shuttle is ready
for departure.
Please sign this to receive medication.
Miporol, extremely potent.
Will keep you functioning
normally until your death.
Please take one pill with each meal.
Thank you for your service.
At 15:00 hours yesterday
you shot down two shuttles,
killing 46 civilians.
Your mandate is to deal
with illegals quietly.
I am aware of that.
And then there is the use of this...
agent.
A Mr. M. Kruger.
15 human rights violations...
Rapes, kidnappings, torture.
The man's been diagnosed with
serious psychological issues.
We made it explicitly clear to you,
that we're no longer using
sleeper agents.
Tell me something,
President Patel.
Do you have children?
I'm not the one being reviewed here.
Then I will assume you do not.
Perhaps, if you did have children,
then you would behave in a manner
that is more conducive
to the longevity of this habitat.
I understand,
it is not the fashion
to think and to act as I do.
I understand that perfectly.
But when they come for your house...
or the house you built
for your children...
And your children's children...
It won't be PR,
and campaign promises
that keep them out.
It will be me!
I've heard enough!
This is your final warning.
Any further unauthorized actions,
and you will be removed from office.
And let's discharge this...
agent Kruger permanently.
All in favour?
Good.
Effective immediately.
You want some beer?
You have been discharged from CCB.
Please return all weapons
to local embassy.
Fuck your Politikster!
Fuck you!
Look...
Max...
Max!
What's wrong?
What happened?
Jesus, let me help you.
Let's go. Come on.
Max, what happened?
I should not have gone in, man.
Gone in where?
I took a full dose, man.
A full dose.
You're gonna be ok.
Let me help.
You're gonna be ok, Max.
They gave me Miporol, man.
They gave... They gave me...
Miporol.
I got five fucking days, man!
I only got five days!
You have to take this.
They can fix this shit on Elysium, man.
I know.
I'm gonna go see Spider.
Max, Max!
Take the pill!
There you go!
To see Spider, you need money.
I'll give you everything I have,
but it's not enough for a ticket.
He's going to give me a ticket.
He's gonna give me a fucking ticket.
Frey, you know we've done everything
we could to help your daughter.
But I had a meeting today with the board,
and they're recommending that
we send her home with you.
How can I work here
and leave her at home?
You know it can happen
any minute, Dr. Faizel.
I know, I know,
if she has another seizure,
of course bring her back to the board,
of course.
But until then she's discharged.
This isn't Elysium.
We can't just heal her.
Max!
It's been a while, my brother!
How's life at the factory?
I need to ask you a favour.
What? I can't hear you. What?
I need a ticket. Up there.
And an ID.
Yeah. Yeah, sure. Sure.
Absolutely.
You prefer aisle or window?
I'm being fucking...
serious, man.
Listen, I'm gonna come back
I mean come back and work for you.
Anything you need.
I'll fucking pay it back.
You know what?
This...
is...
priceless.
This is priceless.
Yeah, let me ask you a question.
Do you have...
Do you have any idea,
how many idiots,
come in here saying
the same kinda bullshit?
That.
I got little kids,
coming here every day.
Max,
if I were you,
I'd get the fuck out of here,
right now
Max stop.
Let's go! Let's go!
¡Vámonos! ¡Vámonos!
Max. No.
I did 3 years for you.
Everything I did, I did it for you,
you're gonna get me up,
you're gonna get me up.
Can you feel this?
Go ahead and shoot.
I got so much radiation
in my body right now,
you're probably getting
a little sick yourself.
You really dying?
I'm fucking dying, motherfucker.
See this?
It's over. I put the gun down.
Put the gun down!
Get out of here!
Ok!
Listen,
I've been looking for
someone to take a job for me.
But no one here had the balls.
You said you'd do anything,
right?
Max...
Ok.
I'm ok.
This...
my friend,
this...
can be your ticket up there.
One last job for me,
you earn your way up.
What is it?
Take an Elysian asshole,
right?
A billionaire,
who's down on Earth for some business...
He's, he's here for, whatever.
We hijack him.
Fuck that!
Relax.
The guy's like...
much worse.
Forget his watch,
forget his ride, forget all that shit.
This,
is what you take.
Organic Information,
right out of his head.
I'm talking about bank codes,
passwords,
login data.
Access to billions.
All you have to do,
is plug into his brain,
download the data
to yours with this baby,
and bring it to me.
This is crazy Max.
Come on.
Once we verify the data,
I'll give you a one way ride,
all expenses paid.
Even throw in some snacks and a drink.
All you have to do is,
walk into a house
and use the med-bay,
and you're cured.
Sandro will do the surgery.
You know him?
Fuck...
Jesus Christ!
I'm good.
Actually,
you seem all weak.
And fucked up so...
You know what?
I... I have...
Them...
This is crazy.
Install...
Let's get out of here.
Please, listen to me.
What the fuck am I gonna do?
I'll have them install...
This!
A third generation Axo-suit.
We hook this into your nerval system,
and it'll make you as strong as a droid.
You're already under the knife, right?
Let's get out of here, please.
I want a 4 man team.
But I pick them.
I'm sending my own data wrangler.
Brain to brain, that is...
real tough.
Ok, but I'm taking Julio.
He gets a ticket up there, same as me.
Yeah, sure.
Ok, I'll go get the boys ready.
Wait!
It's got to be John Carlyle.
The CEO of Armadyne, Carlyle?
That's the mark.
Secretary Delacourt,
Mr. Carlyle has arrived.
You are here to...
persuade me to renew our
Armadyne contracts, yes?
Astute as always.
Come with me.
I'm not interested in your little ideas.
I am interested in something
much larger.
This habitat is dying.
There is a political sickness inside of it.
A tumor that needs to be removed.
You and your company,
are in need of revenue
that is drying up.
So...
You built the Torus.
Can you override the servers and
place a new president in power?
A coup?
Are you suggesting a coup?
Is it possible?
I could write a reboot sequence.
It'd shut down the entire system,
and at that point...
you can encode a new President, yes.
Then that is what you will do.
And you will have your contract
secured for the next 200 years.
Missile Defense Batteries,
Droids, everything we need,
to protect our liberty.
All guaranteed, of course,
by your new President.
Go! Get to work, Mr. Carlyle.
This is the guy.
He's the guy?
This is him.
Sit down.
We're gonna cut you up good, homie.
Play nice, amigo.
Play nice.
Let's get him an ID first.
Give the chief one
of my identification codes.
Get that ready.
Arm up.
And we'll merge it with the DNA.
Now you fit in.
Like you were born there.
Now it's time for the real fun.
Hey, man?
Yeah.
This gonna hurt?
Yeah bitch, it's gonna hurt.
It's gonna hurt good.
When we're done with you,
you're gonna be a ninja.
Mariana!
Bring down the bone saw!
This ain't gonna kill me.
You'll be airight. Not bad.
Max.
I'm here.
We got this, man.
We got this?
Yeah!
Hey!
He's awake!
El está despierto!
Made it?
Surprise!
You can still jack off, alright?
How's everything going?
Ready to kick ass?
What the fuck did you do to me?
Gave you a way out.
What's up, partner?
How's that suit working out
for you man?
That shit is tight!
Show me.
Hold this.
Is it a family heirloom?
Wait for it.
Air-bursting ammunition.
Designate your enemy...
and any round you fire will
explode around a 5 meter kill radius.
And...
safe detonation rounds for this bad boy.
That'll work.
Move out!
Sir...
Your shuttle is ready.
Do you read me?
Yes.
Alright, here's the deal.
We'll wait outside the factory
until we see the shuttle leave.
One of you opens
an explosive round in it,
goes to the crash site
and gets the data.
Ok, copy that.
Camera's live, boys.
You getting this, Spider?
Alright now, let's go!
Let's play ball!
Get away!
You nervous?
No.
No?
I'm shitting myself with fear.
Me estoy cagando de miedo.
I'm not gonna fucking die.
No.
Go, go, go!
Acceleration to supersonic speed
in 15 seconds.
Come on, come on, come on, come on!
Critical engine failure.
Ma'am, we have an Elysium citizen
on Earth in danger.
Data coming up now...
Citizen identified.
John Carlyle. N8321.
I see you, motherfucker!
I have a situation here.
Kruger, do you read me?
Ms Delacourt.
How lovely to hear your voice.
There's a citizen carrying sensitive
brain data out of the city right now.
Some thieves are trying to hijack it.
What's in it?
That's classified.
You don't call a recently deactivated,
agent to retreive classified
fucking information!
The government doesn't know
about this, do they?
I can ask for whatever I want, can't I?
Please brace for impact.
Please remain calm.
You have sustained zero injuries.
Oh, that's a real comfort.
I've got one condition.
I do this, I get re-instated.
Fine.
I've recommissioned 2 of your
preferred agents completely
confidentially, of course.
They should be at your
position any second.
Send me the mission data.
Let's go, guys.
Out of the cars!
Droids, there appears to be,
some type of wheeled vehicle with one...
Two occupants.
They are armed and I'd like them dead.
Droid!
It's jammed! It's jammed!
No!
Identified, Max da Costa.
Federal Parole number
61492-8-557.
It's jammed, man!
Got it!
He's reloading!
Guys!
We got the bastard!
I got you covered!
Let's go! We got you covered!
Go, go, go, go, go!
Don't fucking move.
Bring it!
There's another one!
Die, motherfucker!
Don't hit the mark!
No, no, no!
He got hit! He got hit!
Citizen has sustained
a cardio-thoracic trauma.
Blood pressure is dropping.
It's not in the head!
Is he breathing?
No, no, it's in the chest!
Well, fucking good, man.
Hold his head, hold his head.
Let me see your brain.
I plug this into you.
Come on, come on, come on!
Yes.
Is it working?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, we're syncing.
We're syncing.
You have...
have no idea...
what you're doing.
One minute to target, sir.
We're syncing.
Come on, baby, here we go.
It's gonna work. We got it.
It's gonna work.
It's a data heist, ma'am.
They're downloading now.
Guys, we've got incoming.
Fuck me!
Come on, guys, hurry up.
That's a Raven.
That's Military.
Alright we got this, 97.
We got 98!
Hurry up, they're coming.
Almost there! Almost there!
99!
In!
Here we go!
Shit!
Data must be corrupted!
What the fuck?
What does that mean?
Wait. Hold on. Hold on.
I can't read the data.
It's scrambled!
What?
Come on, guys! We got to move!
What the fuck does scrambled mean?
Fuck this!
No, no, no, no! Run it again!
Run it another time!
Fucking get off me, man!
I'm fucking bailing!
Please. Run it again.
Fuck you!
Let's get out of here.
Come on, let's get out of here.
Where the fuck are you going,
Sandro?
Let's get outta here!
Goddammit! Come on, man!
Come on Max.
Get out of there! Let's go!
We got to go!
Come on, Max! Come on!
Hey boss, we got a runner.
Locked on.
Fire!
That's what I'm talking about!
Fuck, man!
Target moving south-southwest.
Move back!
It's coming!
We got another one.
Again!
This is wrong! This is all wrong, man!
Going into holding pattern, sir!
Where do you think you're going?
Fuck!
Motherfucker!
Come on!
No!
No.
Get up!
No!
We've got one assailant leaving on foot,
ma'am.
They have the data.
Repeat:
The thieves have the data.
Apprehend the target at all costs.
Do not damage his brain.
Let's go! We got a runner, boys!
The citizen has suffered catastrophic
blood loss leading to cardiac arrest.
Time of death, 17:45.
Come on, where are you hiding?
What's that?
Looks like a herd of pigs, boss.
Fuck you, man!
Find him!
Take us back to the crash site,
to see what they left behind.
Roger, that.
Thank you.
Gracias.
Hey boss,
I think you better come look at this.
This is a record of what we picked up
being transferred between
Carlyle and the criminals.
That's why she wants it so badly.
He's got the keys to the kingdom
in his fucking head!
Now we just need to find him.
Gonna let the girls out.
Searching grids 3 through 11.
I'm authorising a Full Containment Order.
Issue a No Fly Zone for Los Angeles.
All of Los Angeles?
The murderer's still out there.
Until we apprehend him,
no one leaves the surface of that city.
What the f...
Max.
Hey, sweety!
Hey.
We can go home.
Am I better?
I'm gonna get the car.
Ok?
Be right back.
Frey...
Max!
My God, what happened to you?
Shit, I'm gonna get the medics.
No, no!
I can't go in there.
Max!
Max, listen me,
I can't go in...
You need a doctor, ok?
People are looking for me.
They're gonna kill me.
I came here for you. I need your help.
Max!
You've got to go through
the system to get treatment.
Please help me.
I don't wanna die.
Max!
Stay awake!
I wanna see the man.
Mama's gonna help him, ok?
Try and sleep.
Don't sleep!
You're too heavy for me, Max.
Eres muy pesado para mí, Max.
Help me!
Ayúdame.
Come on!
Max, you can do it, come on!
No, wait.
Let's turn you over!
Max.
Max, wait.
Thank you.
Who did this to you?
I don't know.
I got hurt at work and...
I had to take a job,
from Spider to try to get up there
and get healed.
It went, it went bad,
now I'm in trouble.
Mommy?
Hey sweety,
come here!
Who is that man?
His name is Max.
Mommy knew him when he was your age.
It's Matilda.
Hi!
You can go watch cartoons, ok?
I'll be right there.
I didn't know you had...
I'm so sorry, I need to go.
Wait, Max wait.
You can not leave. Wait.
I should not have come here.
I have to leave!
Max! She's dying.
I can't...
She's in the final stages of leukemia.
I told you my life complicated.
I need you to help me.
I've no idea how to do this.
How to do what?
Get her to Elysium.
I can't help her. I...
Listen...
I would if I could.
How about this?
Fake citizenship.
If you took her there,
could you heal her with this?
It doesn't work that way.
This is coded to me,
it's locked to my DNA.
Thise people are looking for me. They...
You don't understand
who these people are.
If they find me here,
they will kill all of us.
The only thing I can do
to help you is leave.
I promise you.
She's all I have.
I'm sorry.
You have bandages.
Yeah. I got bandages.
What are you doing?
I don't want you to be sick.
You wanna hear a story?
N...
There once was a meerkat
who lived in the jungle.
He was hungry...
and he was small.
So small.
And the other big animals
had all the food,
because they could reach the fruits.
So he made friends with a hippopotamus.
Ok, stop!
It doesn't end well for the meerkat.
Yes, it does
because he can stand
on the hippopotamus' back
to get all the fruits that he wants.
What's in it for the hippo?
The hippo wants a friend.
I'm sorry.
Hey, boss.
I think we got him.
Yank this fucking cunt!
Mommy, is everything ok?
It's ok, sweety.
Clear!
What is this?
Good afternoon.
Sorry to come bursting into your home.
Didn't mean to...
traumatize your young daughter.
Me and the boys here are,
looking for a young gentleman...
who was in this very house
a moment ago.
We're hoping you can tell us
where he went.
No.
I...
I don't know where he is.
I don't believe...
in committing violent acts
in front of the kids.
So I just need you to close your eyes,
sweetheart.
It's ok.
I really need you to tell me.
Hey?
You remember now?
Mommy!
Close your eyes,
keep your fucking eyes closed.
Keep her eyes closed.
Please, I don't know where he is.
He was wounded,
I helped him and he left.
Please!
Do you fucking hear that?
No loyalty nowadays, hey?
What's this here?
This a hospital you're running here?
What's going here?
She's sick.
She's sick?
She's sick let me have
a look at her, alright!
Don't touch her.
See that? Protective instinct, here!
I said don't touch her!
I'm just trying to get a word
with your child.
Don't touch her!
Bring her. Come!
Where are you taking her?
Now I've got something you want.
Sweety, it's ok.
It's ok, darling. It's ok.
Sit down!
Shut up!
Stop!
No, no, don't shoot him!
¡No, no, no, no lo maten!
Put the gun down!
Let him come!
You got something, didn't you?
What?
That's why they shut down the sky.
What is it?
Wire transfers? Corporate intel?
You got to have something big in there!
No.
I fucking got nothing, man!
It all got scrambled.
Julio is dead. You owe me.
Let's go fucking now!
We can't!
The flight system is jammed!
Nobody is going up there.
Until when?
Till I don't fucking know.
I got to fucking get up there, man.
I got to fucking get up there!
Everyone needs to get up there.
My guys are working on it!
See if they have a hope in hell,
which I personally think we do not,
of ever getting back online.
But,
for now...
Let's just...
take a look at that head of yours.
Get away from me, man!
Look at me,
if they shut down,
the whole fucking sky,
for what's in your head...
Maybe,
the key to opening it,
could be in there too, right?
Come on.
Alright.
They will hunt you,
to the edge of the world for this.
What is it?
It's a reboot program for Elysium.
Whoever has this, has the power
to override their whole system.
Open the borders...
Make everyone...
a citizen of Elysium.
This...
can save your life.
We can save everyone.
When can I go?
They're trying to hack through
the signal jam, but soon...
Don't bullshit me, when can we go?
I don't no.
Five days...
a week?
Fuck you.
I don't have 5 days!
I got hours.
My guys are working on it.
You're always working on it, man.
You don't.
You can't get me up there.
I don't even know why you try
sending people up there man,
they just get fucking shot down.
Not with what's in your head!
That's what I'm talking about!
We would control the system.
We would be in charge!
We can change the course
of fucking history!
To back up then.
What I have in my head,
is worth a lot to them, right?
Don't do this.
If that falls into the wrong hands,
they could shut us out for good.
Listen man,
I'm going up there right now.
Now if you can find me and I'm healed,
you can have all of this.
But I'm not fucking dying.
This is wrong Max, don't do this.
Don't shoot him! Don't shoot him!
It's ok.
I always wanted a wife.
Just couldn't quite settle down,
you know?
Too much temptation.
But you...
You make me ready to settle down.
You really make me want
to settle down, baby.
Holy shit, sir.
You better come take a look at this.
What is it?
Check this fucking oak.
Turn us around.
Take it.
Right, sir.
Open the door.
Stop right there,
and you're gonna do exactly what I say.
Or I'm gonna blow my fucking head off,
you understand?
Yeah!
You can have everything in my head!
Just take me up there,
and get me in a med-bay.
What I have is very valuable.
We can fix you up.
Put you in a med-bay,
sort all this cock-up.
Let's go!
We'll take you up there.
Weather's nice, air's nice and clean.
Likely you'll dig it.
Don't you fucking try anything!
Step aboard!
Come meet the boys,
come on!
Don't be shy, they won't bite.
Let me introduce you.
This is Drakie. This is Max.
What is news?
Let's fly!
Yes ma'am,
we apprehended the subject.
Open the skies, we're coming up.
I'll expect you in 19 minutes.
Cancel the No Fly Zone.
Yes, ma'am.
Hold it...
Hold it. What is that?
Are we back?
Marcelo! What the fuck is that?
We're back online, Spider.
Frey...
I'm sorry.
I'm gonna make this right.
We've got him.
Alright. Where is he?
He's leaving Earth.
Heading to Elysium.
Manuel!
Rico!
Get weapons!
Let's get up there.
Echo leader 234, requesting
landing in sector 22.
Roger that Echo leader 234.
You are clear for entry...
I see you got the G-1 there.
Hey, back the fuck up!
Are you...
Back the fuck up!
Or what?
I'll let it go.
What you gonna do?
I want what's in your head, boy.
Kill him!
Grab him, Deck!
Take the grenade!
Get out!
What do you want us to do, ma'am?
I want everyone coming out of that
vehicle apprehended by Homeland Security.
Evacuate everyone on the level five
clearence out of the building, now.
Max!
I warned you of this.
An unlicenced vehicle just crashed
potentially threatening the Torus.
All because of your inability to act.
Evacuate him.
Get your hands off me.
This is an act of war.
That puts the CCB under my control.
Now, if you'll let me do my job.
I'm sure you have,
a fund raiser to attend.
Let's go, sir.
Max!
Why don't you answer me, here?
Por qué no me contestas, aquí!
Max!
Take me out of here, Max!
I'm trying!
Air quality reaching toxic levels.
Get me out of here!
It is recommended you exit
the craft immediately.
Run!
Come here!
Fuck!
2 Illegals heading northeast in zone 3.
You deal with those two.
I'll handle this pussy.
Welcome to the spectacular
properties from your...
Error.
No I...
No!
No citizen detected.
No detected.
Please she's sick, help us.
She's gone into a coma.
Please!
Shouldn't we remove this thing?
Can't, till we get all the data.
It's wired into him neurologically.
The data is intact, yes?
Data looks intact.
Warning.
We can still pull this data out of him,
which will kill him.
Oh, it's fine.
How long before you can download
and turn the system online?
Not long, Ma'am.
Keep everything in a restricted cloud.
Lock down all access.
Starting prep right now.
And get these...
two out of here.
Roger that.
Kurt,
you wanna go get the boss' chicks?
Yeah, good.
Give them the runaround.
Keep them busy.
Got him!
Let's go!
Alright. 50 exabytes, buddy.
Are you ready?
What are you taking out of him?
Hey!
What're you doing to him?
What's gonna happen to him?
Hey!
Rise and shine.
Get up!
Max.
Max. Max.
Max!
Get in there!
Yes.
Boss got fucked up?
Ate that fucking grenade!
His brain is fine. But he's gonna
be pissed when he wakes up.
Remember what cock-up happened
in India when he lost his hat?
Kruger?
Boss?
It's Crowe.
Where is he?
Alright, all set.
Ok. Let's reach the data.
I got the needle prepped too.
You wanna grab this?
Grab the needle! Grab the needle!
Grab the needle! Grab the nee...
Where did they take the girls?
The Armory.
Where the fuck is that?
Level three.
Lethal radiation poisoning detected.
You require urgent medical attention.
You idiot!
Do you realize what you've done?
You crashed an unlicensed vehicle
into a suburban area.
Your orders were to keep this covert.
Do you even remember what that means?
Have you completely lost your mind?
You're useless to me.
If the administration realized
what we're doing,
they'd hang us both for treason.
For God's sake, Kruger!
Are you listening to me?
Yes.
Yes, ma'am.
I'm listening.
I'm sorry...
that we crashed the vehicle
and ruined someone's lawn.
But nobody is gonna hang us
for treason.
We do the hanging!
Put your hand on it,
keep pressure on it.
Don't leave.
How tough you be now?
It's alright, boys.
Elysium is about to get
its first proper president.
She needs some medical attention.
I was gonna heal your daughter.
But now, I'll make sure she's never healed.
Drakie, don't trust
any of those politicians!
Clear out this whole building!
Thank you, boss.
I'm gonna find that little gangster.
I'm gonna take what's in his head.
This place is mine now.
You want to come to my fucking
house and play?
Let's play!
I'm going to annihilate
that little motherfucker.
I'm going to pulverize that little one.
Hey!
What the hell was that?
All members of CCB.
Please go to the nearest exit.
Proceed calmly to ground level.
Move, move, move, move!
Go, go, go, go, go!
No.
Citizen deceased.
Please exercise caution.
Illegals detected in multiple locations.
Emergency systems are now online.
Please follow indicated procedures.
Spider!
Do you read me, Spider?
Max, where are you.
The thing in my head,
it can make everyone
a citizen here, right?
Yeah.
You know how to get it out, right?
Yes.
You're sure?
Yeah, I'm sure.
Ok, listen to me carefully.
Armory selected.
Set.
Turn me on.
Ok.
Crowe.
Get rid of those two.
My pleasure, boss.
My pleasure.
Where are you, Boykie?
Where are you?
How is it, girl?
Let's play.
No.
No, please.
I'll be nice, I'll be gentle.
I promise.
Come on.
Get off me.
Want me to hurt the girl?
No.
Then come here.
Please.
Fuck!
Fucker!
The only way out of here is through me.
Is she alive?
For now.
Stay behind me.
I'm gonna get you out of here.
I have a plan.
Do you hear that sound?
That's the sound of me coming for you.
I'll find you!
I'll hunt you down!
Ok Frey, we have to split up.
What?
Listen.
You're gonna go to the surface.
Ok, take this.
Alright. Find a house.
Get her to a med-bay.
Max, it won't work.
Don't stop. Don't stop...
She doesn't have an ID.
It doesn't work.
It will this time.
I know how to fix it.
Surface selected
Go.
Come with me.
I'm right behind you.
No.
I promise.
Ok.
A mother and her daughter,
just went up in that elevator right there.
They're going to the surface,
they're headed for a med-bay.
Send one of your guys
whether make sure they get there.
And we have our deal.
Alright.
Right to a med-bay, man.
Let's go.
Go, go, go!
This way!
Come on!
Come on. This way.
Hurry up, man.
Emergency lockdown initiated.
Almost there.
What's that?
It's just a flesh wound, butch.
That's what I'm talking about.
Fire has been detected.
All affected areas will be shut down
Hold the door! Hold the door!
Come on! Come on! Come on!
I got it. Go, go, go, go, go.
Come on. Let's go.
Fucking door, come on!
Go! You first. Come on!
Emergency lockdown initiated.
Come on.
Please stand clear of all exits.
Max! Stand up!
Come on. Let's go!
Get up. Get up.
Stand up. Come on.
Stand up!
Hey!
You little fucker.
I'm gonna take your fucking head off!
Dude, you should definitely stand up now!
No!
Stay there.
Fuck!
Ok.
You think you can get through me?
Come on, Max!
Come on!
I'm just getting started.
Come on.
Don't give up now.
Get up, come!
You want more than this?
I know you.
You look a little bit dizzy?
Did I get you?
Are you bleeding?
You must get that looked at.
Hey, boykie?
You wanna heal that little girl?
You just need to come through me.
You got some fire in you, boykie.
You almost had me.
We die together, boykie.
Ok.
Come on, man, let's go.
Let's go, man, let's do it.
Come on!
Ok. Let's go.
Get the door, now!
Come on.
Alright.
Let's do it.
Hurry.
Ok, we're good, we're good.
We're good.
What?
Max.
It's ok. I know.
There's no coming back from this.
No med-bay can heal you.
Alright, give it to me.
Take it.
Ok.
You just have to press...
that button.
Frey?
Max?
Max where are you?
I'm gonna have to break my promise.
I can't make it back up there.
You remember what I said
when we were kids?
Yes.
I'll take us there one day.
Really?
Yeah, I promise.
You would not believe
what I'm looking at right now.
Tell Matilda I really liked her story.
And..
I figured out why the Hippo did it.
Come on!
You go first. Come on!
Everyone have something special, Max.
Todos tenemos algo especial, Max.
Something we're already destined to do.
Algo que ya estamos destinados a hacer.
Something for which we were born
Algo para lo que ya nacemos..
Neutralize him.
Fuck you!
Let go of me!
Come on, please.
Hey, little girl, my love.
Hey, chiquita. Mi amor.
Hey.
Stand down, Officers.
Arrest him.
I can not arrest a citizen of Elysium.
What?
You did a great job.
Guess who Elysium belongs to now?
Do you see how beautiful it is from here?
¿Ves lo hermoso que nos parece desde aquí?
Now see how beautiful we look from there.
Ahora ve lo hermosos que nos vemos desde allí.
Now it belongs to you.
Ahora te pertenece.
So you never forget,
Para que no olvides nunca,
where you come from.
De dónde vienes.
My little Max.
Mi pequeño Max.
By LESAIGNEUR
Sync & corrections July 2020